Guide to the Andover Newton Theological School Alumni Files
Yale University Divinity School Library
Andover Newton Theological School Alumni Files
1810-2013
RG 278
Yale University Divinity School Library
50
(50 boxes)
The Alumni files contain information about graduates of Andover Newton Theological School and its predecessors, Andover Theological Seminary and Newton Theological Institution.
Andover Newton Theological School
Arrangement
The files are primarily arranged by year of graduation and alphabetically within each year. The second series contains files that do not relate to specific years.
Biographical / Historical
Andover Newton Theological School was established in 1965 by the merger of Andover Theological Seminary (established 1807) and Newton Theological Institution (established 1825). While maintaining a campus in Newton through 2018 and granting degrees through 2019, it formally affiliated with Yale Divinity School in 2017 and established a presence in New Haven as Andover Newton Seminary at Yale Divinity School.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
From the Andover Newton Theological School Collection, transferred to the Yale Divinity Library in 2017.
Scope and Contents
The Alumni files contain information about graduates of Andover Newton Theological School and its predecessors. This finding aid provides a rough guide to the years of graduation that are included in each box so that boxes can be retrieved from off-campus shelving for more specific investigation. The finding aid will be refined to include all the names of alumni in the future, as time permits. The names provided indicate the first and last folder in each box, to assist with locating individuals when years of graduation may be spread across two boxes.
Andover Newton Theological School; Andover Newton Theological School; Newton Theological Institution; Andover Theological Seminary
- By Year of Graduation, Series I
  - 1810 - 1825 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Abbot, Ephraim - Rood, Heman
  - 1825 - 1832 (Box 2)
    Shaw, Robert - Smith, Samuel F.
  - 1832 - 1838 (Box 3)
    Thompson, John C. - Crowell, William
  - 1838 - 1842 (Box 4)
    Dame, Charles - Woodman, Henry A.
  - 1843 - 1847 (Box 5)
    Adams, Ephraim - Muzzy, Francis Horace
  - 1847 - 1852 (Box 6)
    Palmer, Roswell C. - Moore, John
  - 1852 - 1855 (Box 7)
    Niles, Henry Thayer - Womersley, Thomas
  - 1856 - 1859 (Box 8)
    Alde, Ezra J. - Phillips, Daniel
  - 1859 - 1862 (Box 9)
    Richardson, Henry Jackson - Morse, George H.
  - 1862 - 1866 (Box 10)
    Osborne, Cyrus P. - Gerry, Elbridge
  - 1866 - 1869 (Box 11)
    Hamlen, Chauncey Lewis - Brown, Willard Deming
  - 1869 - 1871 (Box 12)
    Chamberlain, Leander T. - Rowley, Charles H.
  - 1871 - 1874 (Box 13)
    Schauffler, Adolphus F. - Fuhrmann, Jacob W.
  - 1874 - 1876 (Box 14)
    Goodspeed, Calvin - Dyer, Nathan Tirrell
  - 1876 - 1878 (Box 15)
    Eaton, Arthur W.H. - Webster, David
  - 1879 - 1881 (Box 16)
    Ahbrah - Grover, Richard Baxter
  - 1881 - 1884 (Box 17)
    Hall, Lamartine A. - Wyman, John M.
  - 1885 - 1888 (Box 18)
    Abbott, Clifford Belcher - Koyano, Keizo
  - 1888 - 1891 (Box 19)
    Long, Joseph M. - Wilson, Crawford P.
  - 1892 - 1894 (Box 20)
    Adams, Joseph Marion - House, Albert Virgil
  - 1894 - 1897 (Box 21)
    Kingman, Henry - Gustin, Byron Freeto
  - 1897 - 1899 (Box 22)
    Harding, Christopher J. - White, Herbert J.
  - 1900 - 1903 (Box 23)
    Archibald, Adoniram J. - Warner, Albert G.
  - 1904 - 1911 (Box 24)
    Atwood, Alfred R. - Crossland, Edgar
  - 1911 - 1915 (Box 25)
    DesJardins, Wesley H. - Kester, John M.
  - 1915 - 1921 (Box 26)
    Manley, Francis P. - Campbell, Leonard L.
  - 1921 - 1926 (Box 27)
    De Wolfe, R.W.E. - Loucks, Charles H.
  - 1926 - 1930 (Box 28)
    Marcus, Ralph - Jorgenson, Hans G.
  - 1930 - 1933 (Box 29)
    McLean, Baron A. - Eddy, Martha Jane
  - 1933 - 1935 (Box 30)
    Feaston, John Newcomber - Bennett, Stanley A.
  - 1935 - 1936 (Box 31)
    Blok, James - Smith, Willard S.
  - 1936 - 1938 (Box 32)
    Thurmond, Ruth V. - Pearson, Roy
  - 1938 - 1940 (Box 33)
    Pearson, Roy - Martin, Kenneth M.
  - 1940 - 1942 (Box 34)
    McInnes, William G. - Goodale, Theodore N.
  - 1942 - 1944 (Box 35)
    Griffin, Charles W. - Lynde, Arlene
  - 1944 - 1947 (Box 36)
    Ludwigson, Joseph R. - Brown, Russell E.
  - 1947 - 1949 (Box 37)
    Separated Materials
    Cober, William K. - Hevey, Jerome J.
  - 1949 - 1952 (Box 38)
    Hood, Charles F. - Futscher, Roy B.
  - 1952 - 1954 (Box 39)
    Giltner, Fern M. - Armstrong, Norman
  - 1954 - 1955 (Box 40)
    Beede, Harold R. - Smith, Hugh
  - 1955 - 1957 (Box 41)
    Sweeney, Arthur - Niemayer, John
  - 1957 - 1960 (Box 42)
    Rangoon, Richard R. - Klett, Paul
  - 1960 - 1964 (Box 43)
    LeVitre, Robert W. - Yeager, Herbert B.
  - 1964 - 1969 (Box 44)
    Young, Daniel M. - Coffman, Ralph J., Jr.
  - 1969 - 1975 (Box 45)
    Duke, Evelyn Murray - Kilpatrick, David M.
  - 1975 - 1983 (Box 46)
    Litterick, William S. - West, Anne M.
  - 1984 - 2013 (Box 47)
    Adams, Ann - Wiser, Marvin Lance
- Records Relating to Various Years, Series II
  - Miscellaneous (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 50)